<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Amazon Vpc | FARSHI DESIGNS]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/categories/amazon-vpc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-17T02:50:08+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Reza Farshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon VPC Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/27/amazon-vpc/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-27T22:08:11+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/27/amazon-vpc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some Notes about the Amazon VPC service. You will find it useful if you want to prepare for AWS architecture certificate exam.</p>

<p>Amazon VPC:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is like a virtual data center in cloud.</li>
<li>lets you provision a logically isolated sections of the Amazon web service (AWS) cloud.</li>
<li>you have complete control over your virtual network environment.</li>
<li>you can select your own IP address range.</li>
<li>you can create your subnets.</li>
<li>you can configure route tables.</li>
<li>you can setup network gateways ( Internet gateway and Customer gateway).</li>
<li>With VPC you have two level of security:

<ul>
<li>  instance security groups.</li>
<li>  subnet network access control lists (ACLS)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Using Amazon Direct Connect you can connect your corporate data center and your AWS VPC.</li>
<li>There is a default VPC which is user friendly, allowing you to immediately deploy instances.</li>
<li>All Subnets in default VPC have an Internet gateway attached.</li>
<li>Each EC2 instance has both a public and private IP addresses.</li>
<li>If you delete the default VPC the only way to get it back is to contact AWS.</li>
<li>you can user VPC Peering to connect one VPC with another.</li>
<li>when you use VPC Peering , instances behave as if they were on the same private network.</li>
<li>you can peer even VPC&rsquo;s with other AWS accounts.</li>
<li>Peering is in a star configuration.So Siblings VPC&rsquo;s can not directly talk to each other and should use centric one.</li>
<li>Elastic IP addresses, Internet Gateways, VPCs per region : Max 5</li>
<li>VPC connections per region, Customer Gateways per region: Max 50</li>
<li>Route tables per region: Max 200</li>
<li>Security groups per VPC: Max 100</li>
<li>Rules per security group: Max 50</li>
<li>Dedicated VPC&rsquo;s are expensive because all of instance underneath will be dedicated.</li>
<li>When you create a VPC, one route table and one ACL will be created automatically.</li>
<li>Your subnets can not be in different availability zones , just in one AZ.</li>
<li>you can have only One Internet gateway per VPC.</li>
<li>putting an instance in a public subnet is not enough to make public access to that instance.you should assign public IP address to it to make it accessible from the Internet.</li>
<li>For making a NAT instance as a router for routing private subnet traffic to the Internet you should disable source/destination check for that NAT instance.</li>
<li>Access Control list act as firewall and rules are applied to the entire subnet.
*If you don&rsquo;t associate a ACL to a subnet, default ACL which allows all incoming and outgoing traffic will be assigned to a subnet automatically.</li>
<li>Rules in ACL assigned order numbers, so rule #100 evaluated before rule #200. Amazon recommends to increment rules number by 100.</li>
<li>When you create a new ACL, incoming and outgoing traffic is denied by default.</li>
<li>Like as a firewall , Only one ACL can be assigned to the subnet.cardinality between ACL-Subnet is Many to one.</li>
<li>Amazon corporate network is segregated from AWS network.</li>
<li>Port scanning is not allowed in AWS by default. for vulnerability scan you must request it from amazon for a short period.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
