<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Amazon Rds | FARSHI DESIGNS]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/categories/amazon-rds/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-17T20:56:28+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Reza Farshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon RDS Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/27/amazon-rds-notes/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-27T22:04:28+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/27/amazon-rds-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> Some Notes about the Amazon RDS service. You will find it useful if you want to prepare for AWS architecture certificate exam.</p>

<ul>
<li>Amazon RDS now supports these Relational (OLTP): MySQL, Oracle , SQL , PostgreSql, Aurora</li>
<li>Supports Non-Relational No-SQL database , DynamoDB</li>
<li>Supports Data warehousing database (OLAP), RedShift</li>
<li>Supports ElasticCache (fast in-memory cache service), MemCached and Redis</li>
<li>Aurora is a MySql Compatible Database , Not accessible yet.</li>
<li>Aurora provides up to five times better performance than MySQL.</li>
<li>Aurora cost is one tenth that of a commercial database while delivering similar performance and availability.</li>
<li>Aurora start with 10Gb, Scales in 10 Gb increments to 64Tb.</li>
<li>compute resources can scale up to 32vCPUs and 244 Gb of Memory.</li>
<li>Aurora storage is self-healing. Data blocks scanned and fixed automatically.</li>
<li>you can loose 2 copies without effecting write performance.</li>
<li>you can loose 3 copies without effecting read performance.</li>
<li>Maximum Backup Retention Period for RDS is 35 days</li>
<li>When you want restore database to specific time , entirely new database will be created and endpoints will be different from the original database endpoint</li>
<li>you can bring your own license in the case of selecting Oracle and SQL Server as a RDS Engine.</li>
<li>You can modify MySql DB instance and increase storage size , change engine , change database name , password and &hellip;</li>
<li>Microsoft SQL server DB instance has some restrictions:</li>
<li> You can not modify Microsoft SQL server DB instance storage size , Amazon does not support increasing storage on a SQL server DB Instance.</li>
<li> A newly created SQL server does not contain database. you should connect from SQL server management studio and create your database.</li>
<li>The maximum storage size for SQL server DB instance is 1024 GB.</li>
<li>Read replicas are available in Amazon RDS for MySQL, PostgreSQL, and Amazon Aurora.</li>
<li>Amazon RDS for MySQL and PostgreSQL allow you to add up to 5 read replicas to each DB Instance.</li>
<li>With Aurora you will get 6 copies of your data (2 copies in each 3 AZ).</li>
<li>Replication is only supported for the InnoDB storage engine.</li>
<li>When you provision a Multi-AZ DB Instance, Amazon RDS automatically creates a primary DB Instance and synchronously replicates the data to a standby instance in a different Availability Zone (AZ)</li>
<li>you can monitor you Read Replica using CloudWatch Replica Lag statistic. If a replica lags too far behind for your environment, consider deleting and recreating the Read Replica</li>
<li>If you scale the source DB instance, you should also scale the Read Replicas.
<em>you can create ReadReplica1 from MyDBInstance, and then create ReadReplica2 from ReadReplica1.
</em>Before a DB instance can serve as a source DB instance, you must enable automatic backups on the source DB instance by setting the backup retention period to a value other than 0.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
