<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lambda | FARSHI DESIGNS]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/categories/lambda/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-15T00:04:48+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Reza Farshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EC2 Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/25/ec2-essentials/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-25T12:27:57+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.farshidesigns.com/blog/2015/04/25/ec2-essentials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some Notes about the Elastic compute cloud , you will find it useful if you want to prepare for AWS architecture certificate exam.</p>

<ul>
<li>Elastic Compute Cloud provides re-sizable compute capacity in cloud.</li>
<li>It can be scale up or down as computing requirements changed.</li>
<li>EC2 Options: Free Tier, On Demand , Reserved and Spot.</li>
<li>Data Stored on a local instance storage will be deleted when you stop the instance.</li>
<li>EBS backed storage will persist independently of the life of the instance</li>
<li>AWS uses standard technologies detailed in DoD 5220.22-M or NIST 800-88 guidelines for media sanitization to destroy data as part of the decommissioning process.</li>
<li>EBS volume can be attached to only One instance at a time.</li>
<li>Types of storage backed by EBS:

<ul>
<li>  General purpose SSD , 99.999% availability,</li>
<li>  Provisioned IOPS SSD, Designed for IO intensive applications</li>
<li>  Magnetic, Low cost , Suitable for infrequent accessed data</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Identity Access Management (IAM) roles can not be assigned to an EC2 instance after the instance has been created.</li>
<li>You can not add or change roles to an existing EC2 instance but you can change the permissions of a assigned role.</li>
<li>EC2 placement group properties:

<ul>
<li>  group of logical groups of instances in only one singe AZ</li>
<li>  Are low latency ; has 10GBbps network throughput.</li>
<li>  The name you choose for placement group should be unique in AWS account</li>
<li>  Same size instances recommended to be put in a group</li>
<li>  placement groups cannot be merged.</li>
<li>  you can add existing instances to your placement group by creating AMI form that instance and then launch it to your placement group</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Lambda is a compute service which run a code in response of events occurs in your resources and automatically manage that resource for you.</li>
<li>Responses of lambda including capacity provisioning, OS and servers maintenance, security patch , logging and &hellip;</li>
<li>Supported programming language for lambda is JavaScript.</li>
<li>Lambda designed to be available in 99.99%</li>
<li>First one million request of Lambda are free and there after is 0.20 per 1 mil request</li>
<li>Copying snapshots that were encrypted with non-default AWS Key Management Service master keys is not supported at this time.</li>
<li>Snapshots are sent/stored on Amazon S3</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
